A Guide to the Papers of Finlay Forbes Ferguson 1812-1975
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Papers of Finlay Forbes Ferguson 1812-1975
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
MG 50
One Oversize Box
Administrative Information
Access
Open to researchers with the only restriction being that no access to the collection will be permitted for any purposes to any representative of the New York Life Insurance Company or any successor of that company.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Anna Lawrence Redfern Ferguson (Mrs. Finlay F. Ferguson Jr.) and her daughter, Anne Stuart Ferguson Cantile, 1 February 1983.
Biographical/Historical Information
Finlay Forbes Ferguson was an architect and the descendant of a longtime Norfolk family
Scope and Content Information
The collection principally consists of material relating to Ferguson's numerous descendents, including family trees, birth and death registers, correspondence, certificates, receipts, deeds, remembrances, newspaper clippings, and a diary and will. Also, consists of material, notably photographs, relating to Ferguson's involvement in the restoration of several of Hampton Roads' historic houses, including the Willoughby-Baylor House, the Moses Myers House, and the Adam Thoroughgood house. Of special note is correspondence concerning New York Life Insurance Company's payment of insurance claims after intercourse between the United States and Confederacy was declared unlawful in 1861.
Contents List
- Genealogical Materials - family trees, birth and death records (Box-folder 1:1)
- Notes on the family of Henry Dickson and Hannah Longstaff Dickson (Box-folder 1:2)
- Correspondence 1841-1896 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Finlay F. Ferguson to William Finlay Ferguson, May 18, 1841 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Peter Ferguson to Finlay F. Ferguson, October 25, 1860 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Finlay F. Ferguson to his father, March 8, 1896 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Chris Minter to Mrs. Finlay F. Ferguson, Jr., May 1, 1975 (Box-folder 1:3)
- Gibson family papers - correspondence, receipts, ledgers and a list of goods bought at auction(1803-1820) (Box-folder 1:4)
- Family Remembrances 1812-1938 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Funeral announcement - Finlay Ferguson, March 27, 1812 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - "A Description of Myself" by Helen Atkinson Evans Ferguson, October 1890 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - "F. F. Ferguson, A Memorial", November 5, 1936 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Speech by Harrell Ferebee in honor of F. F. Ferguson, May 3, 1938 (Box-folder 1:5)
- Last Will and Testament - Peter Ferguson (Box-folder 1:6)
- New York Life Insurance Company (Box-folder 1:7)
- Report card of Finlay Forbes Ferguson, Woodberry Forest School, March 22, 1924 (Box-folder 1:8)
- Deeds and Indentures (Box-folder 1:9)
- Receipts (Box-folder 1:10)
- Receipts from Williams Wholesale Grocers - C.M. Ferguson and R.S. Broughton (Box-folder 1:11)
- Notes and Payments (Box-folder 1:12)
- Cancelled Checks (Box-folder 1:13)
- "The Custom House" - a three-page description (Box-folder 1:14)
- Little Theater of Norfolk - programs (Box-folder 1:15)
- Miscellaneous (Box-folder 1:16)
  - "To the Customs Officers" (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Drawing of street map and lots (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Handwritten Poem: "The Forest" (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Methodist Catechism 1823 (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Postcard "Many happy returns of the day" (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Financial statement 1866 (Box-folder 1:16)
- Photographs (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Willoughby-Baylor House (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Moses Myers House (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Adam Thoroughgood House (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Norfolk Museum of Arts and Sciences (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Gay 90's party (Box-folder 1:17)
  - "Shad Bake at Joe Walls Cottage" (Box-folder 1:17)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder 1:18)
- Diary (Box-folder 1:19)
- Henry Fitzgerald - Masonic Temple, Baltimore, Maryland (Box-folder 2:1)
- Newspapers (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Baltimore Sun March 7, 1838 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Southern Argus January 30, 1859 (Box-folder 2:2)